We were excited by these results, but then Jim stood up, and what occurred was truly remarkable. All the natural biomechanics mediated by the central nervous system emerged via the synthetic limb as an involuntary, reflexive action. All the intricacies of foot placement during stair ascent -- (Applause) emerged before our eyes. Here's Jim descending steps, reaching with his bionic toe to the next stair tread, automatically exhibiting natural motions without him even trying to move his limb. Because Jim's central nervous system is receiving the proprioceptive signals, it knows exactly how to control the synthetic limb in a natural way. Now, Jim moves and behaves as if the synthetic limb is part of him. For example, one day in the lab, he accidentally stepped on a roll of electrical tape. Now, what do you do when something's stuck to your shoe? You don't reach down like this; it's way too awkward. Instead, you shake it off, and that's exactly what Jim did after being neurally connected to the limb for just a few hours. What was most interesting to me is what Jim was telling us he was experiencing. He said, "The robot became part of me." Jim Ewing: The morning after the first time I was attached to the robot, my daughter came downstairs and asked me how it felt to be a cyborg, and my answer was that I didn't feel like a cyborg. I felt like I had my leg, and it wasn't that I was attached to the robot so much as the robot was attached to me, and the robot became part of me. It became my leg pretty quickly. Hugh Herr: Thank you. (Applause) By connecting Jim's nervous system bidirectionally to his synthetic limb, neurological embodiment was achieved. I hypothesized that because Jim can think and move his synthetic limb, and because he can feel those movements within his nervous system, the prosthesis is no longer a separate tool, but an integral part of Jim, an integral part of his body. Because of this neurological embodiment, Jim doesn't feel like a cyborg. He feels like he just has his leg back, that he has his body back. Now I'm often asked when I'm going to be neurally linked to my synthetic limbs bidirectionally, when I'm going to become a cyborg. The truth is, I'm hesitant to become a cyborg. Before my legs were amputated, I was a terrible student. I got D's and often F's in school. Then, after my limbs were amputated, I suddenly became an MIT professor. (Laughter) (Applause) Now I'm worried that once I'm neurally connected to my limbs once again, my brain will remap back to its not-so-bright self. (Laughter) But you know what, that's OK, because at MIT, I already have tenure. (Applause) I believe the reach of NeuroEmbodied Design will extend far beyond limb replacement and will carry humanity into realms that fundamentally redefine human potential. In this 21st century, designers will extend the nervous system into powerfully strong exoskeletons that humans can control and feel with their minds. Muscles within the body can be reconfigured for the control of powerful motors, and to feel and sense exoskeletal movements, augmenting humans' strength, jumping height and running speed. In this 21st century, I believe humans will become superheroes. Humans may also extend their bodies into non-anthropomorphic structures, such as wings, controlling and feeling each wing movement within the nervous system. Leonardo da Vinci said, "When once you have tasted flight, you will forever walk the earth with your eyes turned skyward, for there you have been and there you will always long to return." During the twilight years of this century, I believe humans will be unrecognizable in morphology and dynamics from what we are today. Humanity will take flight and soar. Jim Ewing fell to earth and was badly broken, but his eyes turned skyward, where he always longed to return. After his accident, he not only dreamed to walk again, but also to return to his chosen sport of mountain climbing. At MIT, Team Cyborg built Jim a specialized limb for the vertical world, a brain-controlled leg with full position and movement sensations. Using this technology, Jim returned to the Cayman Islands, the site of his accident, rebuilt as a cyborg to climb skyward once again. (Crashing waves) (Applause) Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, Jim Ewing, the first cyborg rock climber. (Applause)
Estábamos emocionados con estos resultados pero luego Jim se puso de pie, y lo que ocurrió fue realmente notable. Toda la biomecánica natural mediada por el sistema nervioso central emergió a través de la extremidad sintética como una acción involuntaria y reflexiva. Las complejidades de la colocación de los pies durante el ascenso de la escalera (Aplausos) surgió ante nuestros ojos. Aquí está Jim descendiendo pasos, llegando con su dedo biónico a la siguiente banda de rodamiento, exhibiendo automáticamente movimientos naturales sin él, incluso tratando de mover su extremidad. Dado que el sistema nervioso de Jim recibe las señales propioceptivas, sabe exactamente cómo controlar la extremidad sintética de forma natural. Ahora, Jim se mueve y se comporta como si la extremidad sintética fuera parte de él. Por ejemplo, un día en el laboratorio, accidentalmente pisó un rollo de cinta aislante. Ahora, ¿qué haces cuando algo está pegado a tu zapato? No alcanzas abajo así; es demasiado incómodo En cambio, lo sacudes, y eso es exactamente lo que hizo Jim después de estar conectado neuronalmente a la extremidad por unas pocas horas. Lo que fue más interesante para mí es lo que Jim nos estaba diciendo que estaba experimentando. Él dijo: "El robot se convirtió en parte de mí". Jim Ewing: La mañana después de la primera vez que estuve apegado al robot, mi hija bajó y me preguntó cómo era ser un ciborg, y mi respuesta fue que no me sentía como un ciborg. Sentí que tenía mi pierna, y no era que estuviera apegado al robot tanto como el robot estaba conectado a mí, y el robot se convirtió en parte de mí. Se convirtió en mi pierna bastante rápido. Hugh Herr: Gracias. (Aplausos) Al conectar bidireccionalmente el sistema nervioso de Jim a su extremidad sintética, hemos hecho posible una manifestación neurológica. Mi hipótesis de que, dado que Jim puede pensar y mover su extremidad sintética, y puede sentir esos movimientos dentro de su sistema nervioso, la prótesis ya no es una herramienta separada, sino una parte integral de Jim, una parte integral de su cuerpo. Debido a esta encarnación neurológica, Jim no se siente como un ciborg. Siente que recuperó su pierna, que recuperó su cuerpo. A menudo me preguntan cuándo voy a estar vinculado neuronalmente a mis extremidades sintéticas en forma bidireccional, cuando voy a convertirme en un ciborg. La verdad es que dudo de convertirme en un ciborg. Antes de que me amputaran las piernas, era un estudiante terrible. Obtuve malas notas en la escuela. Más tarde, después de la amputación de mis extremidades, de repente me convertí en profesor de MIT. (Risas) (Aplausos) Mi preocupación es que una vez que esté conectado a mis extremidades nuevamente, mi cerebro vuelva al camino de un yo no tan brillante. (Risa) Pero saben qué, está bien, porque en MIT ya me contrataron. (Risas) (Aplausos) Creo que el alcance del diseño NeuroEmbodied se extenderá más allá del reemplazo de extremidades y llevará a la humanidad a dominios que fundamentalmente redefinen el potencial humano. En este siglo XXI, los diseñadores extenderán el sistema nervioso a exoesqueletos muy fuertes que los humanos podamos controlar y sentir con la mente. Los músculos dentro del cuerpo se pueden reconfigurar para controlar motores potentes, y para tratar de sentir los movimientos del exoesqueleto, aumentar la fuerza humana, el salto de altura y la velocidad de carrera. En este siglo XXI, creo que los humanos nos convertiremos en superhéroes. Los humanos también podemos extender nuestros cuerpos con estructuras no antropomórficas, como alas, controlando y sintiendo cada movimiento de ala dentro del sistema nervioso. Leonardo da Vinci dijo: "Una vez que hayas probado el vuelo, siempre caminarás por la tierra con tus ojos vueltos hacia el cielo,